A Guide to the John S. Griffin Jr. Papers, 1929-1962
John S. Griffin Jr. Papers
1929-1962
Griffin, John S. Jr.
2004-122
7 inches
Archives of American Mathematics, Center for American History, The University of Texas at Austin
These papers document mathematician John S. Griffin Jr.'s education and industrial career.
Biographical Note
Trained as a topologist, Dr. John Sanders Griffin Jr. received his Ph. D. at Tulane in 1956, with a dissertation entitled A Notion of Parallelism in General Fibre Bundles. He taught and completed post-graduate study at the University of Michigan. Later, he joined the staff at IBM's Endicott Laboratories.
Scope and Contents
Most notably, these papers contain Griffin's personal collection of reprints, manuscripts and journals. There are materials in French, Polish, and Greek. Also included are course materials from Griffin's education, and some professional correspondence.
Forms part of the Archives of American Mathematics
Access Restrictions
Unrestricted Access
Index Terms
Griffin, John S. Jr.; Tulane University; Tulane University, Department of Mathematics; IBM, Endicott Laboratories
Detailed Description of the Papers
- Reprints [collected by Griffin]:
  - Geometrie sur les surfaces et les varietes algegbriques (Lefschetz), 1929 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - Acualites Scientifiques et Industrielles: Le Parallelisme Absolu et la Theorie Unitare Du Champ (Cartan), 1932 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - Acualites Scientifiques et Industrielles: La Topologie des Groupes de Lie (Cartan), 1936 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - Acualites Scientifiques et Industrielles: Integralgeometrie (Blaschke), 1935 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - Acualites Scientifiques et Industrielles: Sur les Groupes Classiques (Dieudonne), 1948 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - Rozprawy Matematyczne (Dubikajtis), 1958 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - [Greek Publication] 1958 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - [Greek Publication, copy], 1953 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - Relations entre les complexes de le Rham et d' Alexandre (Papy), 1956 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - Lecture notes of Richard Brauer: Spherical harmonics, undated (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - Session Papers [with annotations], 1959 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
- Manuscripts:
  - Borel on the Leray theory, 1951 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - "Lectures on differential geometry in the large, undated (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - A notion of parallelism in general fibre bundles, undated (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
- Thesis Abstract, Transfinite sequences, ca. 1952 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
- Manuscript, notes, correspondence
  - "The Metrizability of the Bundle Space," 1953-1958 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
  - "Affine Connections in Terms of a Tangent Bundle," 1953-1961 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/1)
- Course materials:
  - "Samelson- Algebraic Topology,", 1949-1950 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/2)
  - "Notes for Mathematics 235, Differential Geometry- University of Michigan, Fall 1958," (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/2)
  - "Vector Analysis Course, Spring 1962," (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/2)
  - ""Eckerman- Differentiable Mainfolds,", 1950 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/2)
- Correspondence:
  - Steve Hu, Wayne State University, "Hu's Manuscript and C; ,", 1957-1959 (Box CDL 1.8/2004-122/2)